# DANISH NASEEM









Https://danishnaseemoid.com | www.linkedin.com/in/danish-n-4a2b7486 | www.github.com/danishnaseem05 | (630) 815-6875 | danishnaseem05@gmail.com

# **Professional Summary**

Skilled Software Developer with over 3 years of experience in computer programming, including designing new programs and applications or editing and improving upon code in existing software programs and applications that will enhance business, in a variety of industries. Extensive experience in creating and managing coding databases, including developing and utilizing code libraries to ease and expedite the coding process. Continually exceeds expectations by building strong relationships and works well with people at all levels of the organization, including stakeholders, customers, vendors, and team members.

### Skills

- Adopting Test-Driven and Behavior-Driven Development
- Running Extensive Tests & Trial Runs
- Collaborating in Cross-Functional Projects
- End-User Oriented & Customer Service Skills
- Efficient & Accurate Coder
- Providing Supplemental Instructions & Diagrams
- Identifying & Fixing Defects
- Mitigating Potential Risk & Generating Reports

- Performing Detailed & Manual Checks of Code
- Customizing Programs to Established Needs
- Results- & Deadline Driven Team Player
- Aptitude for Learning New Technology
- Troubleshooting Errors in Coding or Sequences
- Tracking Industry Trends & New Technology
- Bilingual English & Urdu Communication

### Work History

### Computer Programmer 02/2020 to 12/2020

#### Iowa Reading Research Center – Iowa City, IA

- Successfully supporting the organization by increasing efficiency and service through the construction, maintenance, and streamlining of computing systems and programs, while providing technical support to clients.
- Collaborated with upper management to determine programming objectives, providing model diagrams and prototypes to gain consensus, as well as masterminding the workflow of new programs or expanding existing programs.
- Working on the organization's website and its respective databases, using Moodle API, Php, JavaScript (jQuery and JSON),
   MySQL, and Microsoft Access, while collaborating cross-functionally using Git and GitLab.
- Efficiently creating code in an integrated development environment, supporting programming objectives and providing
  optimal functionality, as well as testing programs, identifying root cause of errors, and fixing faulty lines.
- Handling the work of a Software Developer, including initial software planning, creating flowcharts, debugging code, and designing the application or systems interface, while using code libraries to simplify the writing.
- Supporting data architecture and managing system performance, ensuring code is readable, efficient, and logically
  organized for ease of access, as well as aptly naming variables and including code comments for future users.
- Formulating efficient database retrieval systems and ensuring programs, external equipment, and networks are all in proper communication, while also frequently running upgrades on systems.

### **Video Technician** 11/2018 to 01/2020

#### Bia Ten Network - Iowa City, IA

- Effectively supported pre-game checks and post-game wrap-ups during college sports' live productions including basketball, baseball, softball, wrestling, swimming, and gymnastics.
- Played a key role in monitoring and updating official game stats, in-game replays, graphics, and cameras, as well as proactively ran tests on videos, audio, and signals, including troubleshooting any problems that arose.

 Inspected mountings and electrical equipment to ensure they conformed to health and safety regulations, while installing, operating, maintaining, and repairing video equipment, including media services, cameras, and screens.

Broadcast Software Intern 06/2018 to 08/2018

FCB Chicago - Chicago, IL

- Provided support in the pre-production, production, and post-production of multiple projects, ensuring smooth running, and
  received positive feedback for software development for the Post-Production Department.
- Successfully developed a GUI productivity bot with Python and bash to automate post-production ffmpeg encoding tasks and manage time.
- Worked closely with Media Asset Management, securing existing assets, aiding Editors with assets, working with Creative Services, facilitating the approval process, and handling anything else related to day-to-day production.

# Other Work Experience

Crew Member & Customer Service – McDonald's, Glendale Heights, IL – 2017

### Technical Skills

Java; Python (2 & 3); Ruby on Rails; HTML/HTML5; CSS; JavaScript; Php; SQL; Git; Bash

# Volunteer Experience

Marathon Volunteer - Bank of America, Chicago, IL - 10/2016

### Education

The University of Iowa, Iowa City, IA – 12/2020

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science

Relevant Coursework: Data Structures & Algorithms, Object-Oriented Programming, Software Engineering Languages and Tools, Computer Security, Computer Organization, Discrete Structures

- Developing competence in programming principles and methodologies, problem-solving techniques, and computer systems, while understanding mathematical, logical, statistical, and theoretical foundations of computing.
- Analyzing and comparing the relative merits of alternative software designs and understanding the fundamental principles of computer organization, system software, networks, and security.
- Developing high-quality software systems as well as applying computer science principles to a variety of problems, such as databases, data mining, graphics, and various fields of artificial intelligence.
- Emphasizing not only current techniques, tools, and programming languages but also emerging conceptual frameworks that provide a view of the future.
- Utilizing Python and addressing programming constructs, data types, problem-solving strategies, data structures, objectoriented programming.
- Successfully designing, implementing, and applying data structures such as linked lists, stacks, queues, hash tables, and trees,
  as well as implementing software design patterns including iterators and comparators.
- Developing professional-level programming competence using the object-oriented paradigm and associated concepts of classes, objects, methods, inheritance, and polymorphism.

College of Dupage, Glen Ellyn, IL – 12/2017

Associate degree in Engineering Science; with Honors

• Activities & Societies: Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society

# Selected Programming Projects

For more information on the following projects, check out my Website and/or GitHub page.

Card Game Simulator: This is a SaaS app, providing users with an interface to play an assortment of card games, developed via Ruby on Rails' MVC framework, with SQLite3 as the development database. Supports multiplayer functionality. For the Test-Driven Development Cucumber was chosen for acceptance tests, Jasmine for JavaScript integration tests, and RSpec for unit tests. Agile framework was adopted with GitHub for code collaboration (its Actions used as CI for automating tests), pivotal tracker for user stories, and Microsoft Teams for communication (which includes the weekly scrum meetings).

**Vanpool Service System**: This is a web-based application (created using ruby on rails) that is used to serve as a vanpool service system for the users. It is based on Model, View, Controller framework with SQLite3 as its development database.

**Portfolio Website**: This is my Portfolio website, built using Php 7.4, CSS3, HTML5, JavaScript, and Bootstrap. This showcases my skills, and projects. For displaying each project, a slideshow containing its captioned screenshots is added using Bootstrap's Carousel. **Today's Songs**: This CLI executable program provides the user with top songs of the day, by using Nokogiri Ruby gem to scrape HTML data from two different sites.

**ffmpeg Video & Audio Encoder for FCB Chicago**: Python 2.7 built, executes ffmpeg bash code through pipeline, user-interactive interface, end-result; reducing video/audio file-size while maintaining quality.

### Licensure & Certifications

- Amazon Certified Solutions Architect Professional, Credential ID# E4PJMMK1HM4E1XC4 Issued 08/2020, Valid Until 08/2023
- Amazon Certified DevOps Engineer Professional, Credential ID# 5ED5M49CPMB4QPWB Issued 08/2020, Valid Until 08/2023
- Amazon Certified SysOps Administrator Associate, Credential ID# 53J7YMKKPERQQSW5 Issued 08/2020, Valid Until 08/2023
- Microsoft Certified Azure Administrator Associate, Credential ID# H472-9562 Issued 07/2020, Valid Until 07/2022
- JavaScript for Web Designers LinkedIn Issued 08/2019, No Expiration Date
- Learning from Failure LinkedIn Issued 08/2019, No Expiration Date
- Node.js Essential Training LinkedIn Issued 08/2019, No Expiration Date
- Artificial Intelligence Foundations: Machine Learning LinkedIn Issued 07/2019, No Expiration Date
- Get Ready for Your Coding Interview LinkedIn Issued 07/2019, No Expiration Date
- Programming Foundations: Algorithms LinkedIn Issued 07/2019, No Expiration Date
- Programming Foundations: Data Structures LinkedIn Issued 07/2019, No Expiration Date
- Programming Foundations: Design Patterns LinkedIn Issued 07/2019, No Expiration Date
- Intro to SQL for Data Science, Credential ID# 9781851 DataCamp Issued 06/2019, No Expiration Date